Overview of the G. I. Fil'shin Interviews
Hoover Institution Archives
G. I. Fil'shin interviews
1987-1997
98003
Fil'shin, G. I. (Gennadii Innokent'evich)
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Sound recordings and transcripts of interviews conducted by Tatiana Zhilkina, relating to political conditions and especially to economic policy in the Soviet Union and Russian Republic. Includes some biographical materials on G. I. Fil'shin.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1998.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Russian economist; deputy prime minister, 1990-1991.
Scope and Content of Collection
Sound recordings and transcripts of interviews conducted by Tatiana Zhilkina, relating to political conditions and especially to economic policy in the Soviet Union and Russian Republic. Includes some biographical materials on G. I. Fil'shin.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Soviet Union--Economic policy--1986-1991.; Soviet Union--Politics and government--1985-1991.; Russia (Federation)--Economic policy.; Russia (Federation)--Politics and government.; Phonotapes.; Zhilkina, Tatiana.
Partial Collection Contents
- Sound recordings, DATES
  - Sound recordings from a hotel in Moscow and answers to questions for Klub magazine, 1989 August 4 - September 24 (Box 2)
    Part 1: Hotel in Moscow, 1989 August 4. Part 2: Answers to questions for Klub magazine, 1989 September 24. Use copy reference number: 98003_a_0006929
  - Sound recordings, 1991 May 30 - September 19 (Box 2)
    Part 1: Meeting at the ministry, 1991 May 30. Part 2: 1991 September 19. Use copy reference number: 98003_a_0006930
  - Sound recordings, 1987 October 10 - 1988 November 2 (Box 2)
    Part 1: Why was the Baikal-Amur railroad necessary? 1987 October 10. Part 2: On informal groups and local Soviets, 1988 November 2. Use copy reference number: 98003_a_0006931
  - Sound recording, 1987 June 17 (Box 2)
    Recorded in Vienna, Austria. Tape number 1. Use copy reference number: 98003_a_0006934
  - Sound recording, 1987 June 17 (Box 2)
    Recorded in Vienna, Austria. Tape number 2. Use copy reference number: 98003_a_0006933
  - Sound recording, 1987 June 17-18 (Box 2)
    Recorded in Vienna, Austria. Tape number 3. Use copy reference number: 98003_a_0006932
  - Sound recording of Ogonek interview, 1989 November 26; Use copy reference number: 98003_a_0006945 (Box 2)
  - Sound recordings, 1988 November - 1989 July 1 (Box 2)
    Part 1: 1988 November; Literaturnoe Obozrenie, 1989 July 1. Part 2: Continuation of Literaturnoe Obozreni, 1989 July 1. Use copy reference number: 98003_a_0006946
  - Sound recording of Fil'shin speaking about himself and Baikal, 1991 January 25 - February 14 (Box 2)
    Dates recorded are 1991 January 25, February 1, February 12, February 14. Use copy reference number: 98003_a_0006961
  - Sovershenno sekretno and Dobryi vecher sound recordings, 1991 November 22 - December 14 (Box 2)
    Part 1: Recording for Sovershenno sekretno, 1991 November 22 and 14 December. Part 2: Recording from the television show Dobryi vecher, Moskva with Shugaev, 1991 November 1. Use copy reference number: 98003_a_0006962
  - Baikal and Khabarovsk sound recordings, 1991 February 14 - December 19 (Box 2)
    Part 1: Baikal, 1991 February 14. Part 2: Khabarovsk, 1991 December 19. Use copy reference number: 98003_a_0006970
  - Sound recordings of television programs on Lithuania and Supreme Soviet, 1991 January 17-24 (Box 2)
    Recorded from television. Part 1: After the events in Lithuania, 1991 January 17. Part 2: Continuation of part 1 on Lithuania and proceedings of the Supreme Soviet, with a speech by Fil'shin, 1991 January 24. Use copy reference number: 98003_a_0006971
  - Sound recording of Ogonek interview, 1989 November 2-26; Use copy reference number: 98003_a_0006973 (Box 2)
  - Sound recordings, 1989 October 8 - 1991 December 19 (Box 2)
    (1) 1989 October 8; (2) Ending of the book; (3) 1991 December 19; (4) Role of the party and mistakes, 1989 October 8; (4) 1989 October 13. Use copy reference number: 98003_a_0006974
  - Sound recordings, 1989 December 16 - 1990 October 19 (Box 2)
    Part 1: Speech, 1989 December 16. Part 2: Discussion, 1989 December 25; 1990 October 19. Use copy reference number: 98003_a_0006980
- Rest of collection not yet described